<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>import the.world</title>
    <link>http://aaliang.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on import the.world</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 17:06:04 +0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aaliang.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>He&#39;s a Superstar But He Didn&#39;t Get Far</title>
      <link>http://aaliang.github.io/posts/superstar-but-he-didnt-get-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 17:06:04 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aaliang.github.io/posts/superstar-but-he-didnt-get-far/</guid>
      <description>Part of the reason I&amp;rsquo;m in this country is due to a joke, and admittedly it&amp;rsquo;s barely a joke. Gladys Knight&amp;rsquo;s best known song eulogizes the failed career of a small town kid with big dreams in a big city. In the wake of failure, this kid hitches a ride on a midnight train, to Georgia which is presumably his home. This song is perhaps even a mean-spirited farewell as she makes no attempt to veil her pleasure of this kid&amp;rsquo;s misfortune &amp;ndash; in the video her backup singers include a snarky goodbye wave to their dance as if to say see ya later sucka!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfamiliar Loss</title>
      <link>http://aaliang.github.io/posts/unfamiliar-loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 17:31:18 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aaliang.github.io/posts/unfamiliar-loss/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s not much more I can say about this. I can&amp;rsquo;t say that I knew Vanessa well but we were in the same year at BU, former WordStream, and eventual NYC transplants. When I read the news yesterday, I was left with an odd sense of profound sadness. The details have yet to emerge but this is nothing short of a tragedy. I&amp;rsquo;ve always understood that the world was unfair, that good and bad things can happen outside of our realm of control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Falling Back to Earth</title>
      <link>http://aaliang.github.io/posts/falling-back-to-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 17:33:07 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aaliang.github.io/posts/falling-back-to-earth/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been an incredible journey over the last month. Somewhere over either Vietnam or the South China Sea I was ambushed with the irony of flying halfway around the world just to move again a few days later. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t, and still can&amp;rsquo;t believe that this is finally happening.
The sweltering heat is only one of the things you leave behind when traveling roughly 14,000 kilometers from Bangkok to Boston. After a couple days you learn to appreciate any air-conditioned havens you discover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Only Risk Is That You Go Insane</title>
      <link>http://aaliang.github.io/posts/risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 17:14:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aaliang.github.io/posts/risk/</guid>
      <description>I landed in this country 6 days ago. I&amp;rsquo;ve traversed nearly 1,000 kilometers in that span via taxi, pickup truck, ferry, train, subway, mini-van, motorbike, and of course my legs. Just 8 days ago I was still a full-time employee at redacted. 1
It was drizzling when I deplaned at Bangkok&amp;rsquo;s Suvarnabhumi Airport; this came as no surprise as it rains briefly almost every day in mainland SEA&amp;rsquo;s wet season (typically between June - October).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>